PIERRE-OLIVIER PARISÉ

CITIZENSHIP: CANADIAN French (native), English (fluent)

University of Hawai'i at Manōa Dept. of Mathematics Honolulu, Hawai'i, 96822 ☑ parisepo@hawaii.edu ❖ www.mathopo.ca

A university instructor with 8 years of experience in teaching and mathematical research. With my skills in programming, mathematics, and teaching, I am confident I can migrate to many other types of jobs such as a programming job, a financial job, or a management/teaching job in a K-12 school.

SKILLS

Hard skills

- Programming languages (Python, Java, LATEX, HTML, CSS);
- Mathematics (many areas);
- Online Teaching plateforms (Zoom);
- Statistical analysis;
- Grant writing.

Soft skills

- Problem-solving;
- Effective communication;
- Organization;
- Integrity;
- Willingness to learn.

EDUCATION

2021 Doctorate in Mathematics, Université Laval (Québec City, Canada).

Advisor: Thomas Ransford

2017 Master's with Dissertation in Computer Science and Mathematics, *Université du Québec à Trois-Rivières (Trois-Rivières, Canada)*.

Advisor: Dominic Rochon

2015 Bachelor's in Mathematics (Teaching Profil), Université du Québec à Trois-Rivières.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching experience

2021–24 Temporary Assistant Professor, *University of Hawai'i at Manoa*, Current Position.

Courses taught: Linear Algebra, Complex Analysis, Calculus I, Calculus IV, Probability, Differential equations, Introduction to Real Analysis.

Supervision of undergraduate research projects

2024 Quentin Charles. Mathematics major, University of Hawai'i at Manoa.

Project: Bicomplex conjugacy classes and fractals.

Financial support: UROP Entering Research and Creative Work funding.

2022-23 Trey Summers. Program final project, Marine Option Program, UH at Manoa.

Main project advisor : Margaret Anne McManus.

Project: Effects of Tsunamis on Sea Level Along the South Shore of O'ahu, Using Real Time Observations From the Pacific Islands Observing System.

SCHOLARSHIPS, AWARDS AND DISTINCTIONS

Scholarships

- 2022-2024 Postdoctoral Scholarship, National Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada.
- 2021-2023 *Postdoctoral Research Scolarship (B3X)*, Fonds de recherche du Québec Nature et technologies.

Awards and distinctions

- 2022 Nominated for an Excellence in Teaching Award. University of Hawaii at Manoa. Nominated by the members of the department of mathematics for the Excellence in Teaching Award of the College of Natural Sciences at UH Manoa. Declined because I didn't meet the minimum of 3 years appointment condition.
- 2018 Governor General's Academic Gold Medal. Université du Québec à Trois-Rivières.

 Awarded to a graduate student who has obtained the best cumulative average in a university (only one is awarded at UQTR).

PUBLICATIONS

Accepted articles

2023 P.-O. Parisé. Kernel-summability methods and the Silverman-Toeplitz theorem, Accepted for publication in Contemporary Mathematics series of the American Mathematical Society.

Published articles

- J. Mashreghi, P.-O. Parisé, T. Ransford, Power-series methods in de Branges–Rovnyak spaces, *Integral Equations Operator Theory*, 94, paper #20, 2022.
- 2019 G. Brouillette, P.-O. Parisé, D. Rochon, Tricomplex distance estimation for filled-in Julia sets and multibrot sets, *Internat. J. Bifur. Chaos Appl. Sci. Engrg.* 29, paper #1950085, 15pp.

Submitted articles

2024 N. Doyon, P.-O. Parisé, W. Verreault, *Counting Involutions on Multicomplex Spaces*, submitted, 2023.

SOFTWARES

Github https://github.com/popa13

Python Programming

2021 Julia Orbit. Python software, Université Laval.

Github: https://github.com/popa13/Julia-Orbit.

Description : Program for visualizing the iterates of the function z^2+c and their arithmetic means.

Java Programming

2017 3D Mandelbrot-Voyager. Java software, Université du Québec à Trois-Rivières.

Github: https://github.com/popa13/3DMandelbrot-Voyager.

Description: 3D visualization program for Mandelbrot sets.

REFERENCES

1. Rufus Willet, Chair of the math department, University of Hawai'i at Manoa (Honolulu, Hawai'i).

Email: rufus@math.hawaii.edu.

2. Mirjana Jovovic, Assistant Specialist, Director of Undergraduate Studies, University of Hawai'i at Manoa (Honolulu, Hawai'i).

Email: mirjanaj@hawaii.edu.

3. Malik Younsi, Associate Professor, University of Hawai'i at Manoa (Honolulu, Hawai'i). Email: malik.younsi@gmail.com.